王稷尧 Jiyao Wang

www.wangjiyao.top | jiyaowang130@gmail.com Research Interest: Recommender System & Natural Language Processing

SUMMARY

Computer science student and data science enthusiast, dedicated to finding treasure from data.

Experienced in data development, employing algorithms to achieve system optimization or resolving real-world issue, and delivering results on tight conditions. Zealous volunteer passionate about public benefit activities.

EDUCATION

Sichuan University 2017.09 - 2021.06

B.E in Software Engineering

GPA: 3.61 / 4.0

Core Coursework: Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structure and Algorithmn, Computer Network, etc.

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

2021.09 - 2022.06

M.S in Big Data Technology

Core Coursework: Big Data Computing, Data Visualization, Optimization and Matrix Computation, Parallel Programming, Machine Learning, Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery, etc.

PUBLICATIONS

[1]An Multi-Aspect Attentional Model To Capture Multistratal Influence In Social Group, 2021 IEEE International Conference on Electronic Information Engineering and Computer Science (IEEE-EIECS 2021) -accepted

[2] Adersarial Social Recommendation With Capturing Multi-Modal Views Of Social Friends (in Chinese: 基于好友多模态观点的社会化推荐) -processing

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Multi-Aspect Learning To Optimize Extreme Multi-label Text Classification

2021.08 - Present

- Enlightened by my previous social recommendation paper, and detected that existing models also have insufficient modeling capabilities for label parts in extreme multi-label texts, and fail to take into account the aspect-level difference the label population
- Advanced the project in progress under the supervision of Prof.Fangzhen Lin in HKUST, and estimated to complete it in December and published the project paper as the first author

Research Assistant in HKUST Database Reseach Group

2021.09 - Present

• This group is led by Prof.Lei Chen in HKUST. As a team member, I currently participate in the Tecent Al competition which focuses on AutoML in recommendation.

Capstone Project Based on Sichuan Univ. Data Engineering Lab

2020.10 - 2021.05

- Focused on social recommendation algorithm in the project thesis, and honed skills of adversarial learning, multi-embedded feature learning, and attention mechanism in the lab work
- Achieved full marks in the capstone project defense and produced the paper An Multi-Aspect Attentional Model To Capture Multistratal Influence In Social Group after perfecting experiments and theoretical demonstrations on the basis of the capstone project

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Meituan 2021.06 - 2021.09

Autocar Algorithm Intern Beijing

 Utilized C++ to design and develop obstacle decision models, hoping to improve the decision jitter in the face of various types of obstacles

- Applied the clustering method to analyze and simulate the reasons for the jitter in the decision of unmanned vehicles when facing obstacles in the real environment
- Employed Hive SQL and PySpark to complete the evaluation index construction of the obstacle decision model, designed and built the required database and the optimal decision verification set

DiDi 2021.03 - 2021.06

Data Operations Intern

Chengdu

- Using Hive SQL to complete the design and construction of related relational databases, and performing required data extraction; applying machine learning and statistical knowledge to clean up and process the sales data to provide data visualization and conclusions
- utilizing Python to analyze the user behavior data of the platform, and participating in the completion of the platform user hierarchy analysis report

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Sichuan Provincial Statistics Bureau's Innovative Tech Platform

2020.09 - 2020.11

Took charge of platform's construction using PyQt and MySQL for the calculation and display of innovative economic indicators of Sichuan province. Deployed a downloadable Windows APP on cloud servers and obtained the software copyright

ZTE Lanyue Algorithm Competition

2020.04 - 2020.05

Participated in the big data track as an independent contestant, with the title of text semantic information matching. Under the framework of Pytorch, the CDSSM model is improved based on the existing corpus and requirements of the topic, and the recall rate is used to evaluate the index matching accuracy to 0.71

Flight Reservation Big Data Platform

2020.06 - 2020.07

Deployed on 3 Linux servers using Hadoop+Hive, Spark and other frameworks. Completed the construction of the back-end data warehouse and the cleaning and basic analysis of the flight data within half a month, and completed the construction of the web-based platform at the same time

E-commerce Platform Portal Construction Based on JAVA EE

2019.07 - 2019.08

Utilized Java EE and database knowledge to complete the construction of an e-commerce online shopping platform website within two weeks. Completed design and construction of the database and some functional modules, and arranged and coordinated work within the group

HONORS & AWARDS

2020 Merit Student, Sichuan University	2020.09
First-class Scholarship, Sichuan University	2020.09
Successful Participant, 2020 MCM	2020.05
Second-class Scholarship, Sichuan University	2019.09